Preliminary Guide to the Neal E. Miller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - Neuroscience Newsletter - Antivivs. request animal health care records;Sciencebook review on Animal Rights Crusade, 1992 (Box 51)
  - News Articles - 1984: Animal rights, incl. thalidomide (Box 51)
  - New Haven Register - NEM's Op-Ed article and response, 1988 (Box 51)
  - Nicoll-Reines Debate on animal experimentation, 1989 (Box 51)
  - NY Times article by Denise Grady, 9/25/96, and NEM Letter to Editor, 1996 (Box 51)
  - NRC News Reports, 1988 on (Box 51)
  - Nicotine, as reinforcer in rats, suppressed by Philip Morris: Chronology of events, 1994 (Box 51)
  - Nobelists Back Animal Research, 1997 (Box 51)
  - Nutrition [Levitsky's work on malnutrition and behavior], 1985 (Box 51)
  - NYAS [NY Academy of Sciences] - NEM article on Stress-Induced Analgesia (Box 51)
  - NYU - Proactive Action, 1989 (Box 51)
  - Organ Donation Coordinator at Yale [F. Angeletti], 1994 (Box 51)
  - Opposition to pets: by animal rights activists, 1991 (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: Lists and Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: CURE [Connecticut United for Research Excellence, Inc.], 1993 (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR [Foundation for Biomedical Research], general, 1990 on (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR, Board, 1988 on (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR, Meetings, 1987 on (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR, Newsletter (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR, Brochures and Publications (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: FBR, Speaker's Kit (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research:iiFAR [Incurably Ill for Animal Research, 1988 on (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: Medical Scientists' Legal Defense Fund (Box 51)
  - Organizations pro Animal Research: NJ Association for Biomedical Research, 1992 (Box 51)
  - Organizations AGAINST Animal Research: PsyETA [Psychologists for the Ethical Treatment of Animals], 1989 (Box 51)
  - Organizations AGAINST Animal Research: UFETA [Unitarian Universalists for Ethical Treatment of Animals] (brochure) (Box 51)
  - Overmeier, Bruce [University of Minnesota -- work in learned helplessness w. dogs -- activist protest at his home], 1987 (Box 51)
  - Paralysis: Severed spinal cord restored in rats, 1994 (Box 51)
  - Parkinsonism: Arvid Carlsson, 1971 on (Box 51)
  - Partners in Discovery [linking govt., academia, and industry to address animal research issues - Brochure] (Box 51)
  - Partners in Research [Ontario], 1990 on (Box 51)
  - Pasteur and the Invisible Giants -- chap. 15 on hydrophobia, 1958 (Box 51)
  - Pavlov, I. - Biographical sketch and miscellaneous (Box 51)
  - PCRM [Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine -- organization and led by Neal Barnard, a D.C. psychiatrist] (Box 51)
  - Penicillin [Sciencearticle], 1991 (Box 51)
  - Pennsylvania, University of: Head Injury Lab: General, 1985 on (Box 51)
  - Pennsylvania, University of: Head Injury Lab: Research and Evaluation, 1984 on (Box 51)
  - PETA: General, 1985 on (Box 51)
  - PETA and AIDS, 1997 (Box 51)
  - PETA's Animal Housing Violation, 1991 (Box 51)
  - PETA: Chaired monkey "Emblem" Photo, 1992 (Box 51)
  - PETA: Freedom of Speech, Attempt to Stifle, 1990 (Box 51)
  - PETA: Ingrid Newkirk, 1992 (Box 51)
  - PETA: A. Pacheco and I. Newkirk [incl. NIH article on PETA facing possible racketeering charge], 1987 on (Box 51)
  - PETA: Pacheco, Misleads re NEM, Taub, 1990 (Box 51)
  - PETA and PsyETA [articles], 1997 on (Box 51)
  - PETA: University of Pennsylvania Head Injury and Morrison, Adrian, 1993 (Box 51)
  - PETA: Product Testing (Box 51)
  - PETA: Promise of Sanctuary, and Killing of "Rescued" Animals, 1991 (Box 51)
  - PETA's Suit: Pacheco vs. Katie McCabe, 1990 (Box 51)
  - PETA Tactics: Fund Raising (Box 51)
  - Pharmaceutical Research and Development - using Animals, 1979 on (Box 52)
  - Photos, Posters, Placards for 1983 APA mtg. on Value and Ethics of Animal Research (Box 52)
  - Plagues, Origin of [ Science article], 1992 (Box 52)
  - Plum, Fred [Article, etc., re head trauma], 1975 on (Box 52)
  - Poll re Animal Research, 1986 (Box 52)
  - Popular magazines, animal research articles in, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Pound Animals in Research [CFAAR - Coalition for Animals in Research], 1986 (Box 52)
  - Preparation to forestall attacks [by animal activists], 1991 (Box 52)
  - Primates and Rainforests - J. Barbato, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Primate Conservation [Newsletter and Journal], 1987 (Box 52)
  - Primate Research, Value of, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Primate Studies: Yerkes Lab, 1992 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Biomedical Research - AMA White Paper, 1988 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Intro Courses in Psych/Biol[letter fr. Dr. Hubel, Harvard Medical] (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Key People [NEM list] (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Article by S.B. Nuland, Yale Sch. of Medicine, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: NIH Officials and Deans of Associated Medical Schools of NY State [AMS], 1989 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: 30 Nobel Laureates, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Scientists, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Education by Society for Neuroscience [SFN], 1991 (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research Pamphlet: Australian Physiological and Pharmacological Society [incl. NEM's input] (Box 52)
  - Pro Animal Research: Coons' list of Organizations (Box 52)
  - Psychological Research, Use of Animals in British Experimental Psychology Society (Box 52)
  - Quotations from Animal Rights People, 1991 on (Box 52)
  - Randall, W.C. article on Medical Research in Jeopardy, 1983 (Box 52)
  - Reader's Digest [articles on animal research], 1988 on (Box 52)
  - References [typed list from end of unknown paper] (Box 52)
  - Regulations, Excessive, 1983 on (Box 52)
  - Regulations, New, 1991 (Box 52)
  - Representatives and Senators, NEM letters to, re PETA, McCabe, 1990 on (Box 52)
  - Research on Animals: "A True Story" [pamphlet] (Box 52)
  - Research, Basic - "Columns" Journal (Box 52)
  - Research, Hope Through [NIH pamphlets on Amyotropic Lateral Sclerosis, Chronic Pain, Head Injury, Spnal Cord Injury, and Stroke], 1981 on (Box 52)
  - Research on Animals: list of JAMA articles, 1990 on (Box 52)
  - Research on Animals: CERP List [Coalition for Essential Resarch on Primates, incl. Harvard and Yale, 1983 (Box 52)
  - Research Resources Reporter [Journal], 1982 on (Box 52)
  - Research, Animal: Women's Health [FBR pamphlet], 1998 (Box 52)
  - Resources: Databases for Biomedical, Vet., and Animal, and Resource Directory [from Association of American Medical Colleges, Wash, DC] (Box 52)
  - Rights, Animal vs. Human [article by M. Rosenzweig in Nature ], 1985 (Box 52)
  - Rights of Vegetables [from Erewhon by Samuel Butler] (Box 52)
  - Rodin, Judith [letter to NEM as new president of U.PA, on importance of Adrian Morrison's work, 1994 (Box 52)
  - Russell, Ian: University of London, 1988 (Box 52)
  - Sabin, Dr. Albert, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Salk, Dr. Jonas, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Schoolchildren, Education in Value of Animal Research, 1992 on (Box 52)
  - School System, Infiltration of, by Animal Activists, 1985 (Box 52)
  - Schweitzer Institute, 1993 (Box 52)
  - Scientists Attached: John Orem, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Sechzer, Jeri [Paper on Ethical Issues in Animal Experimentation, 1966-84 (Box 52)
  - Security Measures Forced by Raids [NABR], 1986 (Box 52)
  - Selye, Hans - Stress in Health and Disease, History of Stress Concept, 1976 (Box 52)
  - Siegel, Dr. Shepard [McMaster U.,Ontario, Ca], 1985 on (Box 52)
  - Singer, Peter - Draft of letter to Nature in reply to his statements about Taub, 1994 (Box 52)
  - Singer, Peter - "Ethics" article in Ency. Brit., and comments by NEM, Russell and Nicoll, 1992 (Box 52)
  - Society for Neuroscience {SFN] - General, 1983 on (Box 52)
  - SFN: Legal Defense Fund, 1991 (Box 52)
  - SFN: Exhibit Guide, 1990 [Exhibiting Firms and Products] (Box 52)
  - SFN: Grassroots Network, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Sperling, Sally - Article on ALF Break-in at U. of CA-Riverside, 1985 (Box 52)
  - Spinal Cord Injury (Box 52)
  - Stark, Dennis [Rockefeller University draft paper with NEM comments], 1984 (Box 52)
  - State and Natl. Animal Research Associations [CA, MA, FBR, SFN], 1988 (Box 52)
  - Strand, Patti (Executive Director, NAIA = National Animal Interest Alliance], 1993 (Box 52)
  - Stroke Research, 1989 (Box 52)
  - Sulfa Drugs, Discovery of [unpublished NEM paper, including Insulin] (Box 52)
  - Support for Research [Hubel article, Readers' Digest, etc.], 1988 on (Box 52)
  - Survey of Regulations [letter to NEM by American Physiological Society], 1984 (Box 52)
  - Terrorism, General, 1986 on (Box 52)
  - Terrorism: Animal Rights Terrorism Summarized, 1993 (Box 52)
  - Terrorism: Govt. Report, 1993 (Box 52)
  - Tulving, Endel, 1987 (Box 52)
  - "Ulrich, Commentary on" - Ulrich's response to NEM's piece in Psychological Science, 1992 (Box 52)
  - Understanding of Science, Public (Box 52)
  - Unintentional Medical Discovery: Insulin, 1991 (Box 52)
  - USDA: Animal Welfare Enforcement, 1990 (Box 52)
  - U.S. Public Health Service: Protecting lab animals and Role of animal testing, 1992 (Box 52)
  - U.S. Surgical Corp. Value of Animal Research, 1991 (Box 52)
  - Vaccines [Supply and Innovation, Brochure], 1985 (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: Dentistry, 1987 (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: Chronic Pain, 1984 (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: General, 1983 on (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: Key Talking Points [FBR] (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: Brochures, newsletters, incl. Research Resources Reporter and "Better Health through Biomedical Research" (Yale report) (Box 52)
  - Value of Animal Research: Sokoloff letter and reprints on brain imaging, etc., 1994 (Box 52)
  - Vegetarianism, Questions Concerning, 1986 (Box 52)
  - Washington Legal Foundation, 1992 (Box 52)
  - Welfare, Animal: Considerations in Neuroscience Research [article by Wm. Hodos], 1982 (Box 52)
  - White, Dr. Robert [article in Reader's Digest, "Facts about Animal Research"], 1988 (Box 52)
  - "Who Will Live, Who Will Die?" [Katie McCabe article in Washingtonian], and miscellaneous -- "Excellent exposition of animal activists positions and their implications "- NEM, 1986 (Box 52)
  - Yale Public Relations: Yale Bulletin Animal Research Supplements, 1990 (Box 52)
  - Yerkes Primate Research Center, 1990 on (Box 52)
  - Autobiography (first 97 pages)
    - NEM family (Box 53)
    - Photos, early (Autobiog) (Box 53)
    - NEM autobiography, 1999 (Box 53)
  - Misc. Professional Photographs, Circa 1960-circa 1995 (Box 53)